Shwetha Rajaram

shwethar@umich.edu shwetharajaram.github.io University of Michigan, Ann Arbor School of Information

Overview

I study how we can design safer and more privacy-friendly augmented and virtual reality experiences. To do so, I develop novel interactive systems that allow me to investigate the implications of using AR/VR in various application areas and explore methods for integrating privacy guidelines in AR/VR practitioners' workflows.

Research interests: human-computer interaction, AR/VR, privacy & security

Education

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

SEPT 2020 - present

Ph.D. in Information

Advisor: Prof. Michael Nebeling

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

SEPT 2015 - MAY 2019

B.S.E. in Computer Science & Engineering

Publications

Peer-Reviewed Full Papers

<u>Shwetha Rajaram</u>, Michael Nebeling. *Paper Trail: An Immersive Authoring*CHI 2022

System for Augmented Reality Instructional Experiences.

Michael Nebeling, <u>Shwetha Rajaram</u>, Liwei Wu, Yifei Cheng, Jaylin Herskovitz. CHI 2021 XRStudio: A Virtual Production and Live Streaming System for Immersive Instructional Experiences.

Michael Nebeling, Maximillian Speicher, Xizi Wang, <u>Shwetha Rajaram</u>, Brian D. Hall, Zijian Xie, Alexander R. E. Raistrick, Michelle Aebersold, Edward G.

CHI 2020

Happ, Jiayin Wang, Yanan Sun, Lotus Zhang, Leah E. Ramsier, Rhea Kulkarni. MRAT: The Mixed Reality Analytics Toolkit. Best Paper Award

Workshop Papers

Shwetha Rajaram, Michael Nebeling. Extending AR Authoring Tools with	SSPXR@
Built-in Support for Privacy and Security Analysis.	CHI 2022
Shwetha Rajaram, Franziska Roesner, Michael Nebeling. Designing	VR4Sec@
Privacy-Informed Sharing Techniques for Multi-User Augmented Reality.	SOUPS 2021

Teaching Experience

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

Graduate Student Instructor, SI 659: Developing AR/VR Experiences	JAN 2022 - present
Graduate Student Instructor, SI 559: Introduction to AR/VR Application Design	SEPT - DEC 2021
Instructional Aide, EECS 493: User Interface Development	JAN 2019 - MAY 2019

Professional Experience

JP Morgan Chase, Jersey City, NJ	JAN - DEC 2018
Software Engineering Intern	
John Deere, Moline, IL Information Technology Intern	MAY - AUG 2017

Awards

CHI 2020 Best Paper Award	MAY 2020
Society of Women Engineers Outstanding Collegiate Member	OCT 2019
MLK Spirit Award, UM College of Engineering	JAN 2019

Service

Assistant to Program Chairs

UIST 2021

Reviewing

ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI)

2021-2022

IEEE International Symposium on Mixed and Augmented Reality (ISMAR)

2021

Leadership & Outreach

Washtenaw Elementary Science Olympiad (WESO)

SEP 2011 - present

Event Supervisor

Society of Women Engineers (SWE) at UMich

APR 2016 - APR 2019

President, Executive Board Secretary, Executive Board

Summer Engineering Exploration Camp Director

Elementary Outreach Officer

Women+ Excelling More in Mathematics, Engineering and APR 2016 - present Science (F.E.M.M.E.S.)

Website Developer Capstone Activities Coordinator Volunteer

Academic Mentoring

Jihee Yoon, University of Michigan School of Information (Masters)	JAN 2022 - present
Chen Chen, University of Michigan School of Information (Masters)	JUNE 2021 - present
Sereen Kallerackal, University of Michigan School of Information (Masters)	FEB - APR 2021
Maya Subramanian, University of Michigan Computer Science (Undergraduate)	JAN - MAR 2021
I Hun Chan, University of Michigan Computer Science (Undergraduate)	JAN - MAR 2021

Skills

Research Methods: HCI systems research, mixed-methods user studies), user-driven elicitation, interviews, focus groups

Programming Languages: C#, HTML/Javascript, C++, Python

AR/VR Technologies

SDKs: Unity Engine (ARFoundation, Vuforia, MRTK) and A-Frame

Devices: mobile AR, HoloLens 1/2, Oculus Rift, Windows Mixed Reality headsets

Coursework

Ph.D. Courses

Algorithms & Societal Implications, Introduction to Statistics and Data Analysis, Privacy in Information Technology, Human-Computer Interaction, Research Methods, Doctoral Foundation Seminar (*Information Science Theory*)

Masters in Information Courses

Developing AR/VR Experiences, Engineering Interactive Systems, Contextual Inquiry, Graphic Design, Fundamentals of Human Behavior, Game Development Research, Independent Study (AR/VR)

Selected Undergraduate Courses

Game Development, User Interface Development, Web Systems, Intro to Computer Security, Intro to Machine Learning, Data Structures and Algorithms, Intro to Computer Organization, Intro to Computer Science Theory, Interaction Design, Drawing